<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Teaclopedia</string>


    <!-- Pu-erh tea -->
    <string name="what_is_puerh_tea">Pu-erh tea, known as “black tea” in the Far East part of the world, originates from the Yunnan province of China and is named after the market town in which it was first developed. Pu-erh tea is post-fermented, which means that the tea leaves go through a microbial fermentation process after they have been dried and rolled, causing the leaves to darken and change in flavor. This process allows the teas to not only improve with age like a fine wine, but many pu-erhs are able to retain their freshness for up to fifty years! Pu-erh teas can be found in compressed brick form or in loose leaf form and can be made from both green and black tea leaves</string>
    <string name="what_is_puerh_tea_2">Puerh tea is made from a larger leaf strain of camellia sinensis called Dayeh, which are ancient trees with mature leaves that are said to be between 500 and 1000 years old. These trees are usually grown in temperate regions and although they can be harvested year-round, the opportune time to harvest is in mid-spring. Various conditions and environmental factors can impact the flavor profile of pu-erh, resulting in a rich experience for the tea drinker\'s palate of this bold tea that can be smooth, fruity, peaty, grassy, musky, herbal and earthy.</string>
    <string name="pt_history_1">Pu-erh tea can be traced back to the Yunnan Province during the Eastern Han Dynasty. Trade in Pu-erh tea began in the Tang Dynasty, became famous during the Ming Dynasty and was popularized in the Qing Dynasty.</string>
    <string name="pt_history_2">Pu-erh was transported by mules and horses in long caravans along established routes that became known as the Tea Horse Roads. Traders would barter for tea in the markets of Pu-erh County and then hire the caravans to carry the tea back to their respective homes.</string>
    <string name="pt_history_3">The increasing demand for a tea that could be easily transported and did not spoil on long journeys sent suppliers on a frenzy to come up with ways to preserve the tea. It was found that with the fermentation of the leaves, the tea not only kept fresh but it actually improved with age. People soon discovered that pu-erh also helped with digestion, provided other nutrients to their diet, and because it was so affordable, it quickly became a popular household amenity. Pu-erh tea was highly prized and it became a powerful tool for bartering amongst traveling merchants.</string>
    <string name="pt_today_1">Today, pu-erh continues to be regarded as a highly prized commodity. Even in modern society, a well-preserved pu-erh still maintains its value and remains a household treat.</string>
    <string name="pt_today_2">In western society, the popularity of pu-erh tea is only just now being introduced to the mainstream population of tea drinkers, propagated by new hype generated by mass-media about its many salubrious effects. It is only a matter of time before the beauty and benefits of pu-erh tea become commonplace household knowledge.</string>

    <!-- Oolong tea -->
    <string name="what_is_oolong_tea">Oolong (Wu-lung) tea originates from China and is actually transliterated from two words meaning “black” and “dragon” in English. Besides its inherent meaning, the two words describe the shape of the oolong leaves in their novel state. Oolong tea goes through a unique semi-oxidization process that ranges from 1% - 99%. Shortly after picking, the leaves are withered and semi-oxidized in the sun then shade dried. After this, they are basket-tossed to break down the cells on the surface of the leaves and wok-fired, which halts the oxidization process. Heating methods include masterfully hand roasting the tea leaves in multiple steps which generally take place throughout the night. Oolongs are often processed over charcoal or wood which gives a unique flavor to the various finishing styles. Finally, the leaves are curled or rolled into crispy shapes that resemble tiny black dragons, hence the descriptive name. Because oolong tea leaves are more mature, they are harvested later in the spring than green or white teas – usually from late April to early May.</string>
    <string name="ot_history_1">There are numerous theories about how oolong tea came to be.</string>
    <string name="ot_history_2">The first theory, called the “tribute tea” theory, claims that oolong tea stems directly from the Dragon-Phoenix Cake tribute tea, which was made up of two different tea types: “Dragon” (Long) and “Phoenix” (Fong), produced in the Beiyuan tea gardens. When loose-leaf tea came into play as the new way of serving tributes, the name was changed to “Black Dragon” or oolong tea, to associate with the dark, wiry leaves that resulted from this form of processing.</string>
    <string name="ot_history_3">The second theory comes from the “Wuyi” theory, which claims that oolong tea was originally named after the Wuyi mountain region, where it was first documented in poems from the Ming Dynasty.</string>
    <string name="ot_history_4">The third theory comes from the “Anxi” theory, which claims that oolong tea was first discovered in the Anxi region of the Fujian province when a man named Sulong, Wulong or Wuliang, accidentally allowed his tea leaves to oxidize after being distracted during the harvest.</string>
    <string name="ot_history_5">Oolong teas reached the height of their popularity during the Qing dynasty, with the introduction of Ti Quan Yin, or Iron Goddess of Mercy, to the emperor Qian Lung, who was so enamored by the beauty of the tea that word of it quickly spread. This was also about the time that the gongfu ceremonial method of serving tea came about and played an instrumental role in political and modern warfare during that period. Oolong tea was usually served out of special handmade teapots made out of purple clay called Yixing teapots. These were designed to be used with one type of tea only in order to season the teapot and avoid cross-contamination of flavors.</string>
    <string name="ot_today_1">By the mid-1900s, the popularity of oolong teas had grown so much that oolong tea production began in Taiwan. Because of the variable weather and terrain throughout Taiwan, the profiles and overall quality of teas grown there are rather unpredictable and can change dramatically from season to season.</string>
    <string name="ot_today_2">Although the cultivation of oolong tea has spread through various parts of Asia and all the way to India and Nepal in the past decade, the best oolongs today still tend to come from the Anxi and Fujian regions of China or Taiwan and are still best enjoyed using the methods that were crafted during its early inception.</string>

    <!-- Green tea -->
    <string name="what_is_green_tea_1">Green tea, also known as unoxidized tea, is made solely from the leaves of the camellia sinensis plant. The leaves are plucked, slightly withered, then immediately cooked to preserve the green quality and prevent oxidization. As a result of these methods, green teas have a much higher concentration of chlorophyll, polyphenols, and antioxidants than other tea types. The growing conditions for green tea can be broken down between two different types: sun-grown and shade-grown. The leaves are generally harvested three times a year with the first flush producing the highest quality leaves. The heating process differs greatly depending on the region and the tea maker’s techniques.</string>
    <string name="what_is_green_tea_2">Some of the mainstream methods of manufacturing green tea include:</string>
    <string name="what_is_green_tea_3">Pan Firing - Chinese green teas are often pan or wok roasted to neutralize the natural enzymes then dried, which generally results in a pale green color such as our Dragonwell. Steaming – In general, most Japanese green teas are quickly deep steamed resulting in a bright green infusion.</string>
    <string name="gt_history_1">Although written records trace the cultivation of green tea as far back as the Han Dynasty, when its primary use was medicinal, it wasn’t until China’s early Tang Dynasty that we hear of green tea being consumed for pleasure. During this time, green tea was only distributed in compressed cakes for easy transport.</string>
    <string name="gt_history_2">During the Tang Dynasty, there was a groundbreaking book written about the art of green tea drinking called the “The Classic of Tea” or “Cha Jing” by Lu Yu. It is considered one of the most important books of its time because it was one of the first all-inclusive explorations of green tea culture as a whole. It was also during this time that the formal tea ceremony came into being; a ritual, in part due to the tools necessary for preparation, accessible only to the wealthy elite. Because of this, green tea consumption became a symbol of status in society.</string>
    <string name="gt_today_1">While green tea has been consumed longer than any other variant of the camellia sinensis plant, the ways in which it is processed haven’t really changed. In many tea producing countries, green teas are still hand-harvested and hand-shaped, and in some cases with the help of very simple age-old machinery that has been passed down from generation to generation. The ways in which it is consumed, however, have changed drastically.</string>
    <string name="gt_today_2">It wasn’t until the late 19th century that green tea made its way into European and more western cultures. Until the invention of the clipper ship, western cultures were only familiar with black teas, which were the result of freshly harvested green teas that were usually transported via camelback for months at a time by traveling merchants.</string>
    <string name="gt_today_3">These merchants would set up camp night after night, exposing the tea to their nearby campfires, therefore permeating the leaves and giving them a more charred appearance and taste. With the invention of the clipper ships, teas could be transported in less than half the time, allowing them to arrive in a more preserved and unprocessed state. This new method of transport revolutionized the way tea, and green tea, in particular, were perceived and experienced forever. Today, green tea can be found everywhere in the mainstream marketplace in forms from loose leaf to powdered (known as matcha), and in other consumables, such as baked goods and breath fresheners.</string>

    <!-- Red tea -->
    <string name="what_is_red_tea_1">Black tea, also known as “red tea” in China for its rich, reddish infusion, is unique in that it is comprised of two different forms of the camellia sinensis plant: camellia sinensis sinensis and camellia sinensis assamica. Camellia Sinensis Sinensis yields shorter leaves and is primarily used in China and other neighboring East Asian countries. Camellia Sinensis Assamica has larger leaves and is used in parts of India and Sri Lanka. Dry black tea leaves are 100% oxidized, leaving them with a blackened color, thus earning its namesake. While the method in which it is produced varies from region to region, the process always involves withering, rolling, oxidization, and drying. There are two primary methods of processing the leaves before they are graded:</string>
    <string name="what_is_red_tea_2">Orthodox Method – This is the most common method of processing black teas. With this method, more care is put into the tea leaves. After the leaves are picked, they are allowed to wither in the warm air for up to 18 hours to reduce their water content until they are soft and pliable. The leaves are then rolled in a special machine that gently presses and twists the leaves in order to break the cells to begin the oxidization process. This process can take several rounds, depending on the grade of a leaf is cut. After the leaves are cut, they are once again exposed to the air in a climate-controlled environment so that they can continue to oxidize, altering the level of polyphenols in the leaf. This is the point where the flavor of the leaf begins to develop. Once the leaves reach the appropriate oxidization level, they are then fed into a machine to dry, which halts the oxidization process.</string>
    <string name="what_is_red_tea_3">CTC (Cut, Tear, Curl) Method – This method was developed around the teabag boom of the 1950s to facilitate the production of smaller cut tea leaves and quicker processing time. While the production begins and ends in the same fashion with withering and drying, the rolling process is skipped in this method and the leaves are instead minced and broken apart in a rotor vane machine.</string>
    <string name="rt_history_1">Until the mid 17th century (Late Ming, Early Qing Dynasty), the only teas consumed in China were green (unoxidized) and oolong (semi-oxidized) teas.</string>
    <string name="rt_history_2">The tale goes that while a passing army entered the Fujian province, they decided to take shelter at a nearby tea factory. This held up production at the tea factory, where leaves were left out in the sun, causing them to oxidize for a longer period of time and resulting in darker leaves. In an effort to accelerate the drying time, they decided to smoke the leaves over pinewood, thus creating Lapsang Souchong, which became one of the very first black teas.</string>
    <string name="rt_history_3">Although compressed, post-fermented teas (pu-erh) were already known as “black teas” in China, the term was usurped by Dutch and British traders who began identifying Chinese “red teas” as “black teas” because of the color of the dark, dry leaves. Even to this day, Chinese “red tea” is still referred to as “black tea” in the Western world.</string>
    <string name="rt_history_4">What impressed the Westerners most about black tea was not only the robust flavor the tea produced but also the improved lifespan of the leaves over time. And, as British demand for black tea grew, so did the holes in their pockets as they struggled to pay for their tea treasures in a market that was quickly being monopolized by the Dutch. This motivated British traders to explore other avenues for acquiring black tea. After several failed attempts, they discovered a similar genus of the camellia sinensis plant (camellia sinensis assamica) that could be cultivated by machine in India, yielding a bolder crop at a more lucrative return, thus catapulting the Western tea industry to a new level and reshaping our perception of the importance of black tea today.</string>
    <string name="rt_today_1">In today’s market, “broken leaf” black tea accounts for over 90% of all tea sold in the US, the majority of which is enjoyed as iced tea. Also, with the invention of the teabag at the turn of the 20th century, black tea quickly became a household staple and continues to be a popular favorite in the home today. So much so that it’s almost a wonder to the Western world that black tea was ever enjoyed outside of a paper bag with a string attached to it!</string>
    <string name="rt_today_2">Nowadays, with the resurgence of the Chinese economy and the growing wealth of tea knowledge surrounding us, we are once again introducing our palates to the many wonders of black tea and the many dynamic taste profiles it offers. The major production of black tea today stems from India, China, Sri Lanka, and Africa.</string>


    <!-- Yellow tea-->
    <string name="what_is_yellow_tea_1">Yellow tea is produced similarly to white tea and green tea though an additional step is added. This extra step produces a tea that brews into a golden hue and features a mellow flavor without grassy notes.</string>
    <string name="what_is_yellow_tea_2">Yellow tea is a type of tea known as true teas. These types of tea are made from the leaves of the Camellia sinensis plant, known more commonly as the tea plant. Other famous teas in this same classification include green tea, white tea, oolong tea, black tea, and pu-erh tea.</string>
    <string name="what_is_yellow_tea_3">What makes this tea so desirable is its rarity. Yellow tea is a Chinese tea that is difficult to find outside of China. That\'s because the process to produce this tea is time intensity, requires additional labor, and proves to be difficult when it comes to large-scale quality control. As a result, there are only three main types of yellow tea available on the market today.</string>
    <string name="yt_history_1">The origin of yellow tea dates back to the Tang Dynasty. Historically, it was a tribute tea.As an emperor color in traditional Chinese color symbolism, the color yellow represents royalty, power, and prosperity. Yellow is also closely related to gold, which symbolizes nobility and wealth.</string>
    <string name="yt_history_2">Making this type of tea also requires a lengthy and challenging procedure with additional steps evolved from green tea-making methods. As a result, artisans meticulously made yellow using high-quality leaves for the Imperial Court, and only the royalties were allowed to drink yellow tea.</string>
    <string name="yt_history_3">The majority of the yellow tea comes from the high mountains in the four provinces that are also well-known for their green or dark tea, and yellow tea falls between green tea and dark tea in terms of fermentation.</string>
    <string name="yt_today_1">Yellow tea is still the least research tea type in the world, so the scientific data on this tea is still scarce. Just like white or green tea, yellow tea contains antioxidants and caffeine. EGCg, the most important catechin from green tea is present in yellow tea too.</string>
    <string name="yt_today_2">This type of tea will have similar, but not always the same, health benefits as white or green tea. This is because the piling process changes the chemical structure of the tea leaves. Some studies suggest that yellow tea may have increased antioxidant activity. Another study showed that yellow tea may have a higher total phenolic content than many green teas, and all white, oolong, black and dark teas included in the study.</string>


    <!-- White tea -->
    <string name="what_is_white_tea">White tea is comprised of new, young tea leaves and buds from the camellia sinensis plant and is only harvested for a few weeks each spring in the northern district of Fujian, China. The leaves are generally picked in mid-March to early April and only on days when it is not rainy or humid. Just like champagne, white tea can only be called “white tea” if it comes from the Fujian province. White tea gets its name from a silvery type down that covers the leaves and unopened buds, known as “Hao”.</string>
    <string name="wt_history_1">For many years it was believed that white tea was discovered during the Song Dynasty, however, even earlier references to white tea have been traced as far back as the Tang Dynasty. At that time in history, white tea preparation was a very different experience than it is today: early harvest white tea leaves appeared solely in compressed cakes and broken pieces were steeped in earthenware kettles.</string>
    <string name="wt_history_2">Although white tea was popularized and widely revered in the Song Dynasty, it was relatively unknown to the rest of the world until very recently. Only royals were allowed to consume white tea and it is rumored that it could only be served as a “tribute” to the emperor by virgins with white gloves as a symbol of honor and respect. One emperor, Hui Zong, became so enamored by white tea that it literally cost him most of his empire. During this time, ceremonial methods of preparing white tea were very similar to the traditional Japanese tea ceremony for matcha; typically in powder form and whisked in wide ceramic bowls.</string>
    <string name="wt_history_3">It wasn’t until the Ming Dynasty, that the Ming court ruled that only loose leaf white tea could be served as a tribute to the emperor, thus changing our understanding of white tea processing and its preparation forever.</string>
    <string name="wt_today">Modern-day harvesting and preparation of white tea is quite minimal and includes drying and withering of the leaves in one of several methods. These methods include heated vents, wind drying chambers or natural sunlight almost immediately after picking, preventing oxidization. Because of the minimalistic processing involved, many people refer to white tea as a “raw” tea and it is believed to have a higher amount of beneficial properties than green or black teas. The tea withering processes vary from region to region in Fujian and are very much influenced by the environment, both in terms of climate and local traditions.</string>


</resources>